what are headers, headers are additional information sent with HTTP request and response,
thing of them as metadata, about data, simple, simple energy when you send a letter the envelope
as information, return address, sending destination address and with the postage stamp, right.
So, headers are like that envelope information, okay. It is a common request headers,
yeah. It is a common, it is a browser, okay. And it will send the information to the server,
so basically there will be some headers which will be the first header which is basically post,
post header, okay. What does it mean post header? It will tell the server which website you want,
you want and the one server can post multiple websites, okay. So, I want to host like
Google.com. Now, let us see the next header will be our user isn't here,
user, user, user, agent, user, agent, user agent, okay. Our next header will be user agent header.
So, if what will be the user agent, your like identifies your browser and device. So,
your device information and your browser information, okay. Like which versions you want to
invite, right. So, server can optimize content based on this. So, example,
sent, example send mobile version to phone users, okay. So, how application able to know
that you are using phone, you are like looking there contains by using your phone, okay. How?
So, by using this, user agent header, okay. So, it will identify your browser and device
information. Now, next header will be accept header. So, in accept header, it tells what type of
content you can handle. Like saying, I can read only English and Spanish, okay. I can read only
English and Spanish. Now, let's talk about the, okay header. So, over here, over here, the there
will be, there will be session ID, your session ID or your session informations, okay. We will be there.
Session informations will be there. It, it sends stored cookies back to servers more on this below,
okay. And then, it will, it will like send the authorization, the next header will be
authorization header, okay. The next header will be authorization header,
auto, right, session header.
The next header will be authorization header, okay. It contains your login credentials or APIs
prove you, prove you are, okay. So, common response headers will be like server is more
server to browser. Now, let's talk about contain type, okay. Now, let's talk about,
now let's talk about content type, okay. So, in this content type header, sorry. So, in this
content type header tells browser what kind of content it's receiving, HTML page, image,
JSON data, okay. So, that is the part of content type header. Now, let's talk about content, length,
content length, okay. So, in this content length size of response in bytes, okay, like how many
contains would like, would you like to send? So, it's, you want to send three, four, eight contains,
okay, like three, four, eight contains content length, okay.
Then, what will be the next header will be set, okay.
Set, okay, okay. So, in this set, okay, set, okay. So, server as browser to save up, okay,
okay. So, in this, like, server as browser to save up, okay. So, and next talk about
cache control header. So, these are the headers which are very essential guys. So, you need to know
very careful, okay. How these headers works and what kind of information is they just
handling, right, caching, control header. So, in this cache control header,
this browser, it tells browser how long to cache this content, okay. Like if you want,
you want max is like, like, it's, it looks like this, max h, or let's it max a, okay.
Max equals to three, six, double, okay. So, improves, improves performance, okay.
So, and now, our next header will be, will be location header, okay. Our next header will be
location header. So, what will be do, if this location header,
this location header will like, like, it will tells that used with the redirect,
specifically used for redirects, redirects means 3xx codes, okay. And it tells browser where to
go next, okay. It tells browser where to go next. So, here is the, here will be the, like,
I will show you in the demonstration, okay. So, these are the headers which are very, very
essential, okay. First we cover host header, then we cover this as a generator,
then we cover accepted, then we cover cookie, then we cover authorized generator, then we cover
content, content, like, content size, okay. Then we cover content, then we cover set,
okay. Then we cover cache control, then we cover location header. So, these are the headers,
which are variations essential. Now, let's do deep and dive in cookies. So, basically, what are
okay, you can see, these are the content headers, okay. Now, what are these, okay. So, basically,
cookies are small pieces of data that websites stores in your browser, the help website,
remember you, okay. Like, I will tell you the real life analogy. Imagine a coffee shop,
giving you a loyalty card with your name and points. Every time you come back,
they recognize you and know your usual order that what cookie do for website.
Why do we need cookies? The problem will be HTTP stateless. The server doesn't remember you
between request. Every time you click a link, the server thinks, "Who are you?" And I have,
I have never seen you before, okay. So, what will be the solution? The solution will be like cookie,
okay. Cookies, let the server remember things about you. Are you logged in?
What's in your shopping card? Your language preference,
the preference, okay. And how cookies work? So, the step-by-step process. So, the first thing,
first visit, you visit website for the first time, okay. And server sent response with
set cookie header, browser set cookie, okay. And later visit, you visit the same website again,
okay. And browser automatically sent back, sent the cookie, sent the cookie back, okay.
And then, server recognize you. So, let's take an example. First visit, browser,
browser to server, okay. Where, here, show me your webpage. You send the information like,
show me your webpage. And server will respond to browser. Here's the page, also save this cookie,
user ID, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, okay. And second visit, browser to server, hey, show me the page,
show me the another page. Then, it will respond some like, by the way, my cookie says,
user ID, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, okay. Like, you are handling your cookie. And browser will remember you
by seeing your user ID, okay. So, server to browser, like, server, you are sending information to
server to browser, like, server to browser sent the information to you. Oh, hey, I just remember you,
here's your personalized page, okay. So, this is how this will communicate, okay. So, basically,
what are the, like, there are, there are types of cookies, okay. So, the first type of cookie,
like, session management, like session cookies, okay. So, the session cookie, yeah.
And in session cookie, delete, delete it when you, when you close the browser.
Used for temporary things, like shopping cart. And the second cookie will be persistent cookie,
which is basically stay on your device for days, months, years, okay. Used for
remembering mean login features. And the third cookie will be, third cookie will be like,
first party, third will be the first party cookies, okay. So, the first one is,
so the first one is, session cookie, second one is,
persistent, second one is persistent, and third one is like, first party cookie,
first party cookies, okay. Basically, in first party cookies created by the website,
you are visiting generally useful and necessary. And the fourth number is,
fourth party cookie, let's say, fourth party cookie, sorry, it's, it's not fourth party,
it's basically a third party, there will be two parties over there, first one is,
first party and the second one is third party, not fourth party, okay. So, basically,
in third party cookie, created by other domains, like ads analytics, okay. They used for tracking
across websites and often blocked by browser for privacy, okay. Now, there will be
some some cookie attributes, which will be the secure, HTTP only, same site, max age, okay.
And there will be another cookie type, which is the privacy and cookies, like, in modern
concern, concerns tracking your browsing habits, building profiles about you, selling your data,
okay. So, that's why browser cookie now asks, this website uses cookies, accept, would you
like to accept, or not accept, right. So, when you just click up on that app, accept, it can,
It has the ability to sell your data.
Okay?
Thank you guys.